# **TEJAS GOKHALE**

♥ 699 S Mill Ave, Tempe AZ 

tgokhale@asu.edu 

tejas-gokhale.github.io 
Google Scholar

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

I work on computer vision, machine learning, and natural language processing – very often at the wonderful intersection of the three disciplines. My domain expertise lies in *semantic vision*, i.e. building computer vision algorithms that assign "meaning" to what cameras see, with special focus on analyzing and improving the robustness and generalizability of such algorithms.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D.Computer EngineeringAdvisors: Yezhou Yang, Chitta Baral2018–2023M.S.Electrical and Computer EngineeringAdvisor: Aswin Sankaranarayanan2016–2017B.E.(Honors)Electronics and Instrumentation2011–2015

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## O Conference Proceedings

Semantically Distributed Robust Optimization for Vision-and-Language Inference

T. Gokhale, A. Chaudhary, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.07165

ACL Findings 2022

Generalized but not Robust? Comparing the Effects of Data Modification Methods on Out-of-Domain Generalization and Adversarial Robustness

T. Gokhale, S. Mishra, M. Luo, B. Sachdeva, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.07653

ACL Findings 2022

Unsupervised Natural Language Inference Using PHL Triplet Generation

N. Varshney, P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2110.08438

ACL Findings 2022

To Find Waldo You Need Contextual Cues: Debiasing Who's Waldo

Y. Luo, P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.16682

ACL Findings 2022

Improving Biomedical Information Retrieval with Neural Retrievers

M. Luo, A. Mitra, T. Gokhale, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.07745

**AAAI 2022** 

Weakly Supervised Relative Spatial Reasoning for Visual Question Answering

P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2109.01934

ICCV 2021

WeaQA: Weak Supervision via Captions for Visual Question Answering

P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, Y. Yang, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.02356

ACL Findings 2021

Self-Supervised Test-Time Learning for Reading Comprehension

P. Banerjee, T. Gokhale, C. Baral

https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11263

NAACL 2021

Attribute-Guided Adversarial Training for Robustness to Natural Perturbations

T. Gokhale, R. Anirudh, B. Kailkhura, J. Thiagarajan, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.01806

**AAAI 2021** 

Mutant: A Training Paradigm for Out-of-Distribution Generalization in Visual Question Answering

T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.08566

**EMNLP 2021** 

Video2commonsense: Generating commonsense descriptions to enrich video captioning

Z. Fang, T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2003.05162

**EMNLP 2021** 

VQA-LOL: Visual question answering under the lens of logic

T. Gokhale, P. Banerjee, C. Baral, Y. Yang

https://arxiv.org/abs/2002.08325

ECCV 2020

# Workshop Papers / Pre-Prints

Halluci-Net: Scene Completion by Exploiting Object Co-occurrence Relationships

K. Kulkarni, T. Gokhale, R. Singh, P. Turaga, A. Sankaranarayanan

https://arxiv.org/abs/2004.08614

Al for Content Creation @ CVPR 2021

Cooking With Blocks: A Recipe for Visual Reasoning on Image-Pairs

T. Gokhale, S. Sampat, Z. Fang, Y. Yang, C. Baral

Long version: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.12042

Vision Meets Cognition @ CVPR 2019

# Proposal Writing

Decentralized Authorship Attribution

PI: Chitta Baral

Submitted to IARPA, 2022

(Conceptualized and wrote 1 of 3 research plans)

An Active Approach for Data Engineering to Improve Vision-Language Tasks

PI: Yezhou Yang, Co-PI: Chitta Baral

Accepted and Funded by NSF, 2021

(Conceptualized and wrote 2 of 3 research plans)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Research May 2021 - Aug 2021

Research Intern (Mentor: Hamid Palangi)

Lawrence Livermore National Labs, Livermore CA

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Research Scholar

(Mentor: Rushil Anirudh)

Lawrence Livermore National Labs, Livermore CA

May 2020 - Aug 2020

Research Scholar (Mentor: Rushil Anirudh)

Snap Inc., Seattle May 2018 - Aug 2018

Research Intern (Mentors: Guru Krishnan & Shree Nayar)

Carnegie Mellon University

Jan 2017 - May 2018

Graduate Student Researcher (Advisor: Aswin Sankaranarayanan)

#### **TEACHING**

Teaching Associate, Arizona State University

CSE310: Data Structures & Algorithms, Spring 2020, ASU CSE408: Multimedia Information Systems, Spring 2019, ASU Fall 2018, ASU CSE110: Introduction to Programming,

CSE591: Frontier Topics in Vision & Language Course Development [YouTube] [website] Spring 2021 I initiated the development of this class as a series of (weekly) invited seminars, followed by paper reading, discussion, and brainstorming in the classroom.

Student Instructor CTE: Advanced Image Processing, Spring 2015, BITS Pilani

#### **MENTORING**

Ethan Wisdom, Ph.D. CS [current] Maitreya Patel, M.S. CS [current] Huiliang Shao, M.S. CE 2022 [current] Abhishek Chaudhary, M.S. CS 2021 [thesis]

AY 2019-20 Capstone Mentor, mentored five B.S. CS students in projects on vision & language Project Mentor, CSE598 - Perception in Robotics, ASU Spring 2022 Fall 2018 Project Mentor, CSE576 - Natural Language Processing, ASU

#### INVITED TALKS

Mar'22, (Guest Lecture) "Introduction to Generalization in Semantic Vision" ASU CSE 598 Sep'21, (Invited) "Robust Visual Understanding", ASU ML Club Aug'19, "Vision Beyond Pixels", IJCAI Doctoral Consortium, IJCAI 2019, Macao Jul'19, "Reasoning about Objects and Actions via Block-Play", Telluride 2019 Apr'18, (Invited) "Deep Learning Methods in Imaging and Computer Vision", BITS Goa

### SERVICE / LEADERSHIP

Reviewer: NeurIPS (2022), ICLR (2022), ECCV (2022), AAAI (2021-22), \*ACL/Rolling Review (2021-22), WACV (2022), IROS (2022), ICRA (2019-22), IEEE RA-L (2020), Springer MVAP (2020) Organizer, O-DRUM: Workshop on Open-Domain Retrieval under Multi-Modal Settings, [Website], CVPR '22 Organizer, 2021 Frontiers of V&L Seminar Series, [Website], ASU Founder, Summer Vision Reading Group, [Website], multi-university initiative

Volunteer, 2019 Southwest Robotics Symposium. Tempe AZ

Volunteer, International Conference on Machine Learning 2020, Virtual ASU

Advisor, ASU Machine Learning Club,

Mentor, Graduate Student Mentorship Program, ASU Student Mentor, Peer Mentorship Program BITS Pilani

#### **AWARDS**

CVPR 2022 Doctoral Consortium CVPR 2022 ICLR Highlighted Reviewer ICLR 2022 SCAI Doctoral Fellowship (ASU), Spring 2022, Spring 2021, Spring 2020 Engineering Graduate Fellowship, (ASU Engineering), Spring 2020 Graduate College Travel Award, (ASU), for ECCV 2022, ICCV 2021, EMNLP 2020, ECCV 2020 IJCAI 2019 Doctoral Consortium, IJCAI 2019 Inducted, IEEE Eta Kappa Nu, Sigma Chapter (CMU), Jan 2017 National Talent Scholarship (Govt. of India), 2007-2015

## **REFERENCES**

Yezhou YangAssistant ProfessorArizona State University,yz.yang@asu.eduChitta BaralProfessorArizona State University,chitta@asu.eduRushil AnirudhResearch ScientistLawrence Livermore National Laboratoryanirudh1@llnl.gov